{
    "id": "b11d20a2c69a49dba1889ed838e8df4e",
    "title": "Grammar And Vocabulary Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a synonym of read?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "perusal",
                "peruse",
                "persuade",
                "pertain"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The original inhabitants of a state. Give one word",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "locals",
                "migrants",
                "aborigines",
                "fugitives"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I don’t want to argue ………………….. you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "to",
                "with",
                "at"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………… him in October.",
            "description": "When we say when something happened, we use the simple past. ",
            "answers": [
                "met",
                "have met",
                "had met"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "When I reached their home, they ……………………….",
            "description": "To talk about the earlier of two past actions, we use the past perfect. ",
            "answers": [
                "already left",
                "have already left",
                "had already left"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "You ……………………. consult a doctor.",
            "description": "Had better or better had is  used to give strong advice.",
            "answers": [
                "have better",
                "better",
                "had better",
                "better had"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "I am not late, ……………………?",
            "description": "We use an affirmative tag after a negative statement. ",
            "answers": [
                "are I",
                "am I",
                "aren't I"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She has written a story. Change into passive.",
            "description": "In the present perfect we make the passive verb form with has/have + been + past participle form of the verb.",
            "answers": [
                "A story is written by her.",
                "A story has written by her.",
                "A story has been written by her."
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "It is no use ……………………. with her.",
            "description": "An ing form is used after it is no use. ",
            "answers": [
                "to argue",
                "arguing",
                "to arguing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You can take ……………………. of these roads to reach the station.",
            "description": "Either means one or the other.",
            "answers": [
                "either",
                "both",
                "all"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "It has been a long time ……………………. I met him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "from",
                "since",
                "after"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The firemen …………………… the fire in two hours.",
            "description": "To put out is to extinguish. ",
            "answers": [
                "put off",
                "put out",
                "put up"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}